<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-08-10T16:28:07+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Nazli Singh Portfolio</title><subtitle>AWS DevOps Engineer, Cloud Security &amp; AI Enthusiast. Portfolio, blog, and creative work.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Certification Diaries: AWS Certified Security - Specialty Course</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/certification%20diaries/aws/security/2025/08/10/certification-diaries-aws-security.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Certification Diaries: AWS Certified Security - Specialty Course" /><published>2025-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/certification%20diaries/aws/security/2025/08/10/certification-diaries-aws-security</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/certification%20diaries/aws/security/2025/08/10/certification-diaries-aws-security.html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Hosts, Networks, and Not Losing It</strong></p>

<p>I started the AWS Security Specialty this week and, honestly, my brain wanted to back out so quickly, I got mental whiplash. What Am I Doing?! I can’t possibly understand something this complicated… But when starting anything scary or daunting, I took a deep breath and promised to take it one step at a time and see what happens. For the sake of the journey, that’s all.</p>

<p>I’ve started this blog series, “The Certification Diaries”, to take you all along my certification journey and share insights and lessons I learn along the way.</p>

<hr />

<p>To preface this series, I would like to state for the record that there is no RIGHT way or WRONG way to study. Yes, many people will have their opinions and advice, but ultimately, I believe that the way that works for you IS the way that works. I am not working with a strict deadline, but I am working with a structured routine to keep myself on track and focused for the next 90 days. I’ll see how far I get. No pressure!</p>

<p>Ready? Deep Breath. Off we go.</p>

<p>To start the journey off, I am doing the SCS-C02: AWS Certified Security - Speciality Specialisation on Coursera. This course attracted me as it starts off with covering the fundamentals and then moves on to the harder concepts and further deep dives.</p>

<p>This first week has looked at how to keep hosts and networks secure. Or, to put it another way: How to keep the machine itself safe (host security) and keep the streets around it calm and secure (network security).</p>

<h2 id="host-security">Host Security</h2>

<p>I used to think “host security” meant making sure that instances had everything they needed to stay secure — SSM Agent, CloudWatch Agent, Antivirus, Encryption, Backups, Security Groups, NACLs and a big sign saying “KEEP OUT”. Now I see it more like how to keep a child/or pet safe whilst trying to keep the house clean: less stuff, fewer messes, easier to spot what’s off.</p>

<p>Let’s take the EC2 service, for example. This would translate into a few very practical moves:</p>

<ul>
  <li>No long-term access keys on the box. IAM Roles only. If a key lives on disk, sooner or later it’ll end up in a log, a screenshot, or a repo for all the world to see. Can’t be too careful with these kinds of things!</li>
  <li>IMDSv2 or bust. It’s the seatbelt for Instance credentials. It’s cheap, invisible, and the one time you need it, you’ll be glad it’s on.</li>
  <li>Patch without babysitting. Systems Manager (SSM) Patch Manager on a schedule. If I have to “remember” to patch, I won’t.</li>
  <li>Prefer Session Manager to SSH. Fewer open ports, proper audit trail, no juggling key files. It just removes so many sharp edges. If you’ve got to have it, though, make sure to lock it up tightly with the right rules.</li>
  <li>Encrypt by default. Turn EBS default encryption ON at the beginning of creating a new EC2 instance and at the account level.</li>
  <li>Least privilege everywhere: tiny IAM policies, minimal packages, minimal open ports. Teeny tiny chance of terrible things happening to the EC2 instance.</li>
  <li>Central logs: send OS logs somewhere I’ll actually read them (CloudWatch Logs or a SIEM). Like a post-it on the fridge reminding me to get milk and read my logs.</li>
  <li>Known-good baselines: use Systems Manager State Manager or an AMI hardening pipeline so new instances can start securely. Give the instance its best start by giving it values and configurations it can use.</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>Rubber Ducky says: “Give the machine just enough to do its job (IAM Roles), keep it tidy, and don’t leave spare keys under the mat.”</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="some-services-to-help-keep-your-hostsecure">Some services to help keep your Host secure</h3>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Amazon Inspector</strong> is the service that scans your instance for any software vulnerabilities and unintended network exposure. Have you left the metaphorical door unlocked, or are you using a rope to secure your side gate? It’ll create a detailed report about the status and issues with the instance or other resources you have within AWS, such as EC2, ECR and Lambda Functions.</li>
  <li><strong>GuardDuty</strong> does what you’d think it would from its name. Think of it like a neighbourhood watch for your resource logs and data sources. It doesn’t scream unless it sees something actually suspicious. Its main job is to continuously analyse, monitor and process your data and logs by using threat intelligence feeds to protect and prevent potential threats from affecting your resources within your AWS environment.</li>
  <li><strong>CloudWatch Logs</strong> is like the messy drawer where I toss all the logs from EC2, CloudTrail, Route 53, etc… but now it’s a messy drawer I can search and actually find things! You can view, search for any particular error codes or patterns, filter the logs using specific fields or archive for later. Helps to have everything in one place, doesn’t it?</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="network-security">Network Security</h2>

<p>Network security was always an enigma to me. No idea what it was but knew that it’s important and people who understand it are wizards. Now I understand that if I think about it like making sure that the streets in my neighbourhood are secured and safe, that my home is more likely to stay safer too.</p>

<p>Safety and security aren’t flashy and they aren’t supposed to be. The design I like is boring (in a good way): Only the load balancer is public. App and data tiers sit in private subnets. The ALB talks in; nothing else faces the internet.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="more-on-network-security">More on Network Security</h3>

<p>Security Groups over NACLs for most work. SGs are stateful (like a bouncer at the nightclub knows you’re going in and when coming out) and easy to maintain; NACLs are stateless (like a door that only opens from one side) are great when you want a hard deny at the subnet edge. Each type has its uses, but they’re not my daily go-to.</p>

<p>VPC Endpoints are underrated. Hitting AWS services over private connections feels oddly satisfying and reduces your “whoops, that went over the internet” risk.</p>

<p>SGs that reference other SGs keep things readable: ALB-SG → App-SG on app ports, App-SG → DB-SG on the DB port, and that’s it. You can almost read it out loud.</p>

<p>The best “aah, gotcha” moment was around egress rules. In my head, outbound traffic was harmless; in reality, clamping it down plus using endpoints forces apps to talk only where they should. No traffic of mine talking to strangers on the internet streets on my watch!</p>

<p>VPC Flow Logs were the hero. I turned them on, broke a rule on purpose, watched the “REJECT” entries appear, and then fixed the exact line that caused it. That feedback loop trains your intuition fast.</p>

<p>Add ALB access logs when you want HTTP detail; add Route 53 Resolver query logs when you’re chasing weird egress traffic by domain names instead of IPs.</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>“Roles, not keys.”</strong> If I need to copy a secret onto a server, I stop and ask why.</li>
  <li><strong>“IMDSv2 on every instance.”</strong> Set the requirement and forget about it.</li>
  <li><strong>“Does SSH have to come to the party?”</strong> If I really need to SSH onto the EC2 instance, then fine, but try to use Session Manager first.</li>
  <li><strong>“Encrypt everything you can’t afford others to see.”</strong> EBS default encryption makes it more secure if there is a leak from a server/application or a mis-shared unencrypted snapshot. Save yourself some embarrassment.</li>
  <li><strong>“SGs tell a story.”</strong> If I can’t read my Security Groups like a sentence (“ALB can talk to App on 443”), they’re too complicated.</li>
  <li><strong>“Logs before cleverness.”</strong> Turn on Flow Logs and ALB logs; save the packet mirroring and fancy tooling for when you have a clue where to aim them.</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>Rubber Ducky says: “One front door only (LB). Everything else stays inside. Let the bouncers who remember faces (Security Groups) handle day‑to‑day access; save the one‑way doors (NACLs) for hard stops at the street. Take the private hallways (VPC Endpoints), not the sidewalk. Keep the guest list simple.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>What surprised me most was how often “security work” was just removing optionality. Take a little bit off and see what breaks. Put it back and see what works. Locking things down didn’t make the system rigid; it made it predictable and maintainable.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="mini-lab-time-if-youre-up-forit">Mini Lab Time, if you’re up for it!</h2>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Launch a Free Tier EC2 in a private subnet</strong><br />
Type: t2.micro or t3.micro (Free Tier eligible)<br />
AMI: Amazon Linux 2 (already has the SSM Agent preinstalled)<br />
IAM role: Create one with the AmazonSSMManagedInstanceCore policy attached and assign it to your instance.<br />
Tip: Make sure the subnet is private (no Internet Gateway route).</li>
  <li><strong>Connect with Session Manager (no open ports!)</strong><br />
In the EC2 console, do not add an inbound SSH rule.<br />
From the EC2 console, select your instance → Connect → Session Manager tab → Connect.<br />
This works over AWS’s control plane - no public IP or open ports needed.</li>
  <li><strong>Turn on VPC Flow Logs (narrow scope)</strong><br />
Scope: Enable Flow Logs only on the instance’s network interface (ENI).<br />
Destination: Send to CloudWatch Logs.<br />
Retention: Set retention to 1 day so logs don’t pile up.<br />
Filter: Choose ALL so you see both accepted and rejected traffic.</li>
  <li><strong>Tighten a security group rule too far</strong><br />
Edit your security group to block something the instance needs (e.g., outbound HTTPS).<br />
Try to connect to the internet from the instance (via SSM session) - it should fail.<br />
Check the Flow Logs for REJECT entries.</li>
  <li><strong>Loosen the rule just enough</strong><br />
Fix the security group so it allows the necessary traffic.<br />
Test again - the Flow Logs should now show ACCEPT for those connections.</li>
  <li><strong>Clean up when you’re done!</strong><br />
Delete the EC2 instance.<br />
Remove the security group you created.<br />
Delete the Flow Log and CloudWatch log group.</li>
</ol>

<p>This keeps you within the AWS Free Tier and avoids surprise charges.</p>

<hr />

<p>Thank you for making it this far!</p>

<p>I’m eager to hear your stories! How has your study journey gone? What obstacles have you encountered and conquered? What lessons have you learnt?</p>

<p>If you’re looking to dive deeper into these topics or want to share your own story, I’m all ears (eyes?). Follow me on <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/nazli-singh/">LinkedIn</a>. I can’t wait to connect and learn from each of you - your stories are what truly bring these conversations to life!</p>

<p><em>Copyright © 2025 Nazli Singh. All rights reserved.</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Certification Diaries" /><category term="AWS" /><category term="Security" /><category term="AWS" /><category term="Security" /><category term="Certification" /><category term="Cloud" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Week 1 of my AWS Security Specialty journey with practical tips on keeping hosts secure, networks quiet, and avoiding common cloud pitfalls.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sample Blog Post</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/10/sample-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sample Blog Post" /><published>2025-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/08/10/sample-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/10/sample-post.html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a sample blog post. Migrate your existing blog articles here as markdown files. Each post should be named <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">YYYY-MM-DD-title.md</code> and placed in the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_posts</code> folder.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a sample blog post. Migrate your existing blog articles here as markdown files. Each post should be named YYYY-MM-DD-title.md and placed in the _posts folder.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Code and Coping: Navigating Mental Stress in a Hospitality-to-IT Career Shift</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/career%20journey/mental%20health/2024/02/16/code-and-coping-hospitality-to-it.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Code and Coping: Navigating Mental Stress in a Hospitality-to-IT Career Shift" /><published>2024-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/career%20journey/mental%20health/2024/02/16/code-and-coping-hospitality-to-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/career%20journey/mental%20health/2024/02/16/code-and-coping-hospitality-to-it.html"><![CDATA[<p><em>It was 6:30 am, and the sun was rising on a crisp, sunny morning. I could see the rays peeking over the tops of the buildings in the distance whilst I stood in front of the hotel. I remember taking a moment to appreciate the scene, the meaning in the moment, and thinking, “I can’t believe I’m here.”</em></p>

<p>Hospitality was something I fell into. A deep pit in the middle of a forest dug out of nowhere. I dropped in and couldn’t get out—no branch, ladder, or person in sight who could throw me a lifeline. Personal circumstances and pressures had kept me in the profession that, despite falling into, I had learnt to accept and even find moments of fondness for.</p>

<p>As years passed, I remember standing outside the hotel on another early sunny morning. That was the moment it hit me, “I can’t believe I’m STILL here”.</p>

<h2 id="the-spark-discovering-a-new-path">The Spark: Discovering a New Path</h2>

<p>The race to use the computer in our house was inspired by scenes from Mad Max. My parents used it to stay connected with relatives around the world, but I used it for important things like making pretty pictures using Paint, and playing Neopets, and RuneScape (points for guessing the decade). Our primary school IT class curriculum extended to “MS Office” and how to send an email. Didn’t change much in Secondary either.</p>

<p>I’ve always been fairly confident with using a computer and found it was relatively easy to learn new technological skills. At work, I was able to fix everyday technology issues at the Front Desk and found the time to help whenever someone mentioned that “the printer isn’t working”, “the internet isn’t connecting”, or “the server isn’t serving”. The best feeling was when I resolved these issues. I felt like a Superwoman. Which was something I did not feel often.</p>

<p>I never really took thoughts of going into technology seriously. I thought it was a “maybe someday” or “if only” moment I would have on my deathbed. It didn’t help that I hadn’t seen, heard of or known any women in technology in my life at the time. The narrative around technology, planes, trains and automobiles was “That’s for Boys”. Naturally, I thought it was a boy’s thing and that I am a little “tomboy”, a techy nerd who is into stuff like that—and it was okay. I liked that about myself and continue to do so. What really ignited the first “oh, I should really do this” moment was during the COVID-19 lockdowns, when technology personnel and skills were in demand. I also found it encouraging to see industry initiatives to correct inequalities in diversity. As a woman of colour, I thought maybe I could be one of them (maybe?)!</p>

<h2 id="the-leap-decision-to-shift">The Leap: Decision to Shift</h2>

<p>The Hospitality industry had lost its sparkle. Looking down the barrel of another breakdown, I could see colleagues teetering on the edge themselves. If I had learned anything from the COVID-19 lockdown (the one where everyone started baking bread and toilet paper was hoarded for reasons beyond all reasonable understanding), it was that I could not live with this feeling anymore. I felt unfulfilled, demoralised, and unworthy, with a sense of never-ending despair at the thought that I had sacrificed nearly a decade of my life in this career. If I quit, I’ll be a failure and have to start from the bottom all over again. But the shift work, the intense and strenuous work environment, the never-ending Groundhog Day feeling and having to put out fires (metaphorical ones and two real ones) were chipping away at me. It’s not for the faint of heart, that’s for sure, and my heart couldn’t take it for much longer. I needed to make a decision. A DRASTIC decision.</p>

<p>So, I resigned. I QUIT! Without another job lined up or anything apart from a couple of months’ worth of savings I had at the time. I figured that if I gave myself some sense of urgency and started a ticking clock, I’d have no choice but to focus, work hard, hustle, learn, get that amazing technology job—and start paying bills and putting decent food on the table again.</p>

<p>When you start down the Google rabbit hole, there is a mind-numbing amount of technology “Bootcamps” and available courses. Some at a pretty hefty rate, which gives the illusion that once you complete their course/Bootcamp, you’ll be guaranteed a job in technology. I bought into that hype and marketing magic and bought one such set of courses. I also started taking cybersecurity courses (as this is still a field of interest—mainly because I love spy movies and want to learn how to “hack into the mainframe”) and any course I thought would get me closer to employment. But I started this journey without a clear path and could not see the forest for the trees. I was getting frustrated, losing money, losing time and losing my mind to find a way to get my foot in the door. Then, when I thought I would fail, the AWS re/Start programme found me.</p>

<p>When I think back to the person I was when this journey started, she was paralysed with doubt and fear of what the future would bring. She was scared of failure, worried about making the wrong choices and overwhelmed with all the courses she had to finish to be considered “employable”. She knew that things needed to change, and despite being scared, she had the courage to take that leap. Sounds cliché, I know, but they are for a reason. Going through the doubt, changes, and insecurity only made me stronger. I became more resilient, something I knew I had all along but didn’t realise how much of a superpower it was. Adversity and insecurity are something that I’m sure everyone has been faced with at some time or another, but it’s how we deal with it and come out the other side that genuinely shapes us, for better or worse.</p>

<h2 id="overcoming-obstacles-coping-with-stress-and-doubt">Overcoming Obstacles: Coping with Stress and Doubt</h2>

<p>Managing stress and doubt continues to be one of the things that I work on. Stressing and having self-doubt seem to be second nature to the women in my family, and I sometimes wonder if this is a genetic trait. But, on the more than likely chance that it is a “nurture vs nature” point, the ways I manage stress and self-doubt are generally considered simple and widely known. There is no magic or rocket science here, but it requires consistency, patience, and grace towards yourself. Not easy for many people, but for those that do, they swear by it. A few methods that I use are:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Exercise.</strong> I take my dog out for walks for her sake and mine. Taking in nature, fresh air, and light physical exertion is key for clearing my mind after an intense day.</li>
  <li><strong>Reading your favourite book/ watching your favourite movie.</strong> Escapism is fantastic. Immersing yourself and getting carried away in someone else’s life can be fun and give you a break from your own for a while.</li>
  <li><strong>Do something out of your comfort zone.</strong> This was a big one for me last year. I did a few BIG things that scared me, and I can tell you that it was SO worth it. The feelings of excitement and fear manifest similarly, so why not try to turn the things that scare you into things that excite you? Reset your mindset. It’s when you go beyond your boundaries that you grow.</li>
  <li><strong>Listen to Music, play an instrument, or do something Arty.</strong> Get your creative juices flowing and do something that makes your heart sing and gives you creative fulfilment. I usually pick up my guitar, listen to music, tune everything out, or paint a magnum opus (I am very proud of my stick figures).</li>
  <li><strong>Journaling and expressing gratitude.</strong> Writing down thoughts and emotions can be unburdening. Seeing things floating in your mind and taking up your mental energy on paper can help reset your mindset and emotions.</li>
</ul>

<p>Having a support system in place when going through a life change as significant as a career change is invaluable. Understanding the roles and impacts of having a sound support system can sometimes be the difference between getting there sooner or later (or sometimes not at all). This one was a tough one for me in the beginning. Letting people in and sharing concerns, worries, stresses, and frustrations is as healing and energising as sharing your successes and accomplishments.</p>

<h2 id="the-breakthrough-gaining-momentum">The Breakthrough: Gaining Momentum</h2>

<p>In May 2022, I finished the AWS re/Start program and passed my AWS Cloud Practitioner exam. I had the help of their recruiters to send applications to various technology companies and organisations. The process wasn’t all sunshine and rainbows, though. I had a few interviews and a few more rejections, but I had to reassure myself that these setbacks did not define me. I can’t let a little failure stop me. Soon after a string of rejections, I finally managed to get through to the interview stage with Version 1. Since that fateful day, I am forever thankful and hopeful that my future will be bright, and the rest is history.</p>

<p>I don’t know where the time went, but I feel my state of being has vastly improved. My time here so far has seen me going from contributing to small projects to presenting to the entire AWS Platform Team to being a panellist at the “Females of the Future” conference in Leicester Square last year. And it hasn’t stopped there! I am no longer confused about what people mean by CI/CD and this “Jenkins” person everyone seems to know. The moments that I feel like I am no longer on the sidelines learning, than actively taking part in tasks is a self-confidence boost alone. Knowing that you’re no longer feeling like a weak link and can pull your weight within your team is a gear change that sends you flying into the fast lane. It’s encouraging and motivating, and it only makes you crave more of that feeling. The growth and improvement are practically self-fulfilling after that.</p>

<p>The lessons I learnt during this time are that you can’t use shortcuts to get what you want—and if you don’t know what you enjoy, try things out until you do. And it’s okay to change your mind. You can’t punish yourself for having made choices that no longer serve your purpose/goals in life. If your shoes don’t fit anymore, you get new shoes. It’s a simple concept but truly life-changing when put into practice. Changing your mind is fine, and starting again is okay. You live and learn.</p>

<h2 id="the-journey-ikigai-and-the-destination">The Journey: Ikigai and the Destination</h2>

<p>Changing your career late in life is brave, no matter what the stage in life or career, and those years of what may seem like a lost investment can still give returns, should you know how to use the skills and lessons learned in the future. Funnily enough, I was surprised to find that the skills I’d picked up during my time in the Hospitality industry did not fail me. They showed up and helped me to keep going and sometimes even gave me an edge over my colleagues in the program. Time management, learning new concepts quickly and on the go and documenting things concisely and accurately were just a few examples of how my skills were transferable when the opportunity arose. It was a pleasant realisation and reminder that I did not have to consider those years as a write-off.</p>

<p>For those who feel stuck in a career they don’t like, try to find something you do! Ikigai is a Japanese concept that refers to the reason for being or the purpose of life. It helps identify your passions, skills, values, and mission. Knowing these four things can lead you to your own “Ikigai”. Ikigai: The Japanese Secret to a Long and Happy Life is a fantastic book which can help guide you through the process. I loved it, but full disclosure: It does require honest self-reflection. I would recommend giving it some thought and give it a try!</p>

<p>For the fortunate ones wanting to change their career and go into tech? DO IT! But first,</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Do your research.</strong> Learn which courses, skills, and certifications are worthwhile and try to connect with people in the industry to learn more.</li>
  <li><strong>Create a Roadmap.</strong> Learning is a journey; knowing what skills to learn and when to learn them is a good start. Start with the fundamentals and go from there, but roadmap your skills to keep you on task. Look at what skills employers are looking for. What do you have, and what do you need to work on to be eligible?</li>
  <li><strong>Future-proof yourself.</strong> Whether it’s Artificial Intelligence, Virtual Reality, or Quantum computing, staying ahead of the curve is crucial. We must be able to future-proof ourselves to ensure that our skillsets won’t be outsourced to the machine. Research future technologies and learn how you can leverage them in your daily life. Create a project and get hands-on experience with these tools so you have an edge. Get comfortable because AI is here, people! And it’s here to stay.</li>
  <li><strong>It’s who you know.</strong> Don’t hesitate to reach out to people in your network. It can be a treasure trove filled with diverse experiences and insights. People often appreciate being asked for advice and are usually willing to share their knowledge and guidance. Whether it’s for career advice, problem-solving, or exploring new ideas, your network can be an incredible source of support and inspiration. Just remember to be respectful of their time and be open to reciprocating the help in the future.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="reflections-looking-to-the-future">Reflections: Looking to The Future</h2>

<p>I reflect on the choices I’ve made and the journey I’ve been on, and I often remind myself that the ability to change my career at the time I did was privileged. Had I not had some savings to live off for a couple of months, then maybe I would not have made a drastic decision to resign without having a job in place. However, I go on to remind myself that had I not made that decision, I may have ended up in a worse condition. We often find ourselves stuck in a job or career we don’t enjoy, dedicating, on average, 8 hours a day. This doesn’t even account for the time spent commuting or doing extra tasks outside of work hours to maintain our competitive edge. This impact on our mind, body, and spirit is significant, can be sinister, and infringe on our relationships and health. We should be able to cut and run from these conditions without feeling guilty. Taking control of my career and prospects has been, by far, the best decision I have made in my life so far.</p>

<p>I am now gainfully (and gratefully) employed by Version 1 and surrounded by an abundance of supportive, like-minded colleagues who share the same values and are on the cutting edge of technological applications and innovations. As a person who strives for excellence, I believe I have found my place for the foreseeable future.</p>

<p>As AI and cloud technology gain traction in the upcoming years, coupled with the growing demand for a robust cybersecurity workforce, I am channelling my skills and leaning towards specialising in the CloudSecOps and AISecOps fields. It’s a LOT, but I’m incredibly excited for the journey ahead!</p>

<p>Thank you for making it this far!</p>

<p>I’m eager to hear your stories! Have you faced similar challenges or triumphs? Have you walked a path similar to mine, or are you at the crossroads of change? I’d love you to share your experiences and emotions in the comments. Let’s build a community of support and inspiration together!</p>

<p>If you’re looking to dive deeper into these topics or just want to share your own story, I’m all ears. Follow me on <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/nazli-singh/">LinkedIn</a>. I can’t wait to connect and learn from each of you—your stories are what truly bring these conversations to life!</p>

<p><em>Copyright © 2024 Nazli Singh. All rights reserved.</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Career Journey" /><category term="Mental Health" /><category term="Career Change" /><category term="Mental Health" /><category term="Tech" /><category term="Hospitality" /><category term="Women in Tech" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nazli Singh shares her journey from hospitality to IT, overcoming mental stress, and finding meaning and momentum in a new tech career.]]></summary></entry></feed>